Sriram Karthik Akella

OBJECTIVE STATEMENT

I am in the third year of my Bachelor's Degree, majoring in Computing Science. My most recent work experience is working as an Undergraduate Teaching Assistant at the University of Alberta. The projects I have worked on include a realm of Computer Science Technologies, from App Development, Web Development, and Databases to Machine Learning & Artificial Intelligence. Now, I am looking forward to gaining practical experience wherein I can apply the Computer Science knowledge I have gained to a real-world application. I am currently enrolled in the **Science Internship Program (co-op)** at my university, which allows me to work full-time for 4, 8, 12 or 16 months.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python, C, Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Dart

SDKs: Flutter

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, NoSQL

Other Technologies: Git, APIs, Firebase, Android Studio, Xcode. Areas of Interest: Software Engineering, Product Management

Other Skills: Experience with AGILE methods: Scrum

EDUCATION

University of Alberta

Bachelor of Science in Computing Science - Specialization

- Member, Google DSC
- Member, Undergraduate Al Society

WORK EXPERIENCE

University of Alberta

Teaching Assistant

- CMPUT 175: Introduction to Foundations of Computing II
- Conducted lab sessions every week and assisted students in one on one and small group setting
- Assisted teaching staff in designing the course and preparing the lesson plans.

University of Alberta

Science Camp Leader

 Designed and delivered a curriculum for students about robotics, digital design, and basic computer science methods

Undergraduate Association of Computing Science

Junior Representative

- Representative for First and Second Year students
- Prepare and organize the Computing Science orientation
- Management and maintenance of the UACS office

University of Alberta Students' Union

Academic Tutor

• Tutoring students in CMPUT, MATH & STAT classes.

Kuwait Oil Company

Information Technology Intern

- Received practical knowledge on Database and Server Hardware, Cloud Computing, Operating Systems & Computer Networks
- Assisted at the Service Desk of the IT Department of to help employees troubleshoot their issues

Edmonton, AB, Canada Sept. 2020 to June 2024 (expected)

> Edmonton, AB, Canada January 2022 - July 2022

Edmonton, AB, Canada May 2022 - August 2022

Edmonton, AB, Canada May 2022 - Present

Edmonton, AB, Canada November 2021 - Present

Al Ahmadi,Kuwait July 2019 to August 2019

SELECTED PROJECTS

COVID Tracker

February 2021

- Developed a web based application to give a count of daily COVID cases in various countries.
- · Used Python: Flask, urllib
- API used for this project was: https://api.covid19api.com/summary

View project on Github here.

Qify

July 2020

- Developed a mobile application (using Flutter & Firebase) to ease the queuing system at hospitals
- Includes appointment (scheduling, rescheduling, deleting) and video call features.
- This application was developed as part of Kuwait Foundation of Advanced Sciences (KFAS)'s Virtual Hackathon.
- As Team MacBytes, we stood in the top 5 teams (out of 40+ who were selected to participate) to the final round.

View project on Github here.

Smart Weather App

April 2020

- · Displays the weather of a city (inputted by the user).
- Uses an open source API from openweathermap.org
- This application was made using Java.

View project on Github here

Bank Management System

July 2019

- A python menu driven program that runs the tasks of a bank (Creating account, depositing and withdrawing money, closing account, etc)
- Initially made to store data on MySQL Database

View project on Github here

Smart Eye

February 2018

- Used Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligene to develop an assistive device for the visually impaired people, called 'The Smart Eye' which can reduce their dependence on others in terms of mobility
- · Detects and recognizes objects in the field of view of the user. Uses CloudSight API for image recognition
- Received accolades on national level for this project's prototype and invited to participate at World Makerfaire, Bay Area.
 More info. available <u>here</u>